Olive McGehee Denson papers, Inclusive: 1916-1957, undated, Bulk: 1935-1954, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Olive McGehee Denson papers
Inclusive: 1916-1957, undated, Bulk: 1935-1954, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
1444
Denson, Olive McGehee
2 document boxes
The Olive McGehee Denson papers include literary productions, photographic materials, and scrapbooks.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Olive McGehee Denson was born on 1893 September 19 in Cameron, Texas. She was married at the age of 28 to Joe Denson. The couple had one child, Marjorie Denson, born in 1930. The family resided in Milam County, Texas. She died in 1966 April. There is a Baylor scholarship in the Department of Education called the Olive M. Denson Education Scholarship.
Scope and Content
The Olive McGehee Denson papers contain literary productions, photographic materials & scrapbooks. The bulk of the collection are scrapbooks about Texas and church history. There are also photographs from Independence, Texas.
Arrangement
The Olive McGehee Denson papers are arranged in 3 series: I. Literary Productions, II. Photographic Materials, III. Scrapbooks. There was no prior arrangement in the collection prior to this finding aid.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 1444. Acquired 1966-00-00
Related Resources
Related references
"Departmental Scholarships." Baylor University. Accessed 2012 December 2.
United States of America. Department of Commerce-Bureau of the Census. Fifteenth Census of the United States: 1930.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baptists -- Texas -- Grimes County.; Baptists -- Texas -- Milam County -- History.
Places
Independence (Tex.).; Texas -- History.; Texas -- Photographs.
Subjects
Women in church work.
Genres
Church records.; Scrapbooks.
- Literary Productions, 1916-1957; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series includes a notebook of Olive McGehee Denson that contains the church history of Milam County, various publications and bulletins, and a booklet on Texas natural resources. A ledger from Olive Denson is also included in this series. This series is in average condition.
  - Literary: Church History (1 of 4), 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Literary: Church History (2 of 4), 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Literary: Church History (3 of 4), 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Literary: Church History (4 of 4), 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Literary: Notebook (1 of 5), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Literary: Notebook (2 of 5), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Literary: Notebook (3 of 5), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Literary: Notebook (4 of 5), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Literary: Notebook (5 of 5), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Literary: Printed Materials (1 of 3), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Literary: Printed Materials (2 of 3), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Literary: Printed Materials (3 of 3), undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Literary: Natural Resources (1 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Literary: Natural Resources (2 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Literary: Bulletins (1 of 2), 1916-1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Literary: Bulletins (2 of 2), 1916-1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Literary: General, 1934-1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Literary: Ledger, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Photographic Materials, undated; 2
  This series includes photographs from Independence, TX in Box 1, Folder 20, unidentified photographs and a postcard. The Independence photographs include photographs of the Independence Baptist Church and Baylor ruins. Two of the photographs are from Washington on the Brazos State Park outside of Brenham. This series is in poor to good condition.
  - Photographic: Photographs (1 of 4), undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photographic: Photographs (2 of 4), undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Photographic: Photographs (3 of 4), undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Photographic: Photographs (4 of 4), undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Photographic: Postcard, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Scrapbooks, 1935-1954; 3
  General condition: Poor.
  This series includes two scrapbooks. They cover the topics of church history and Texas history. This series is in poor to average condition.
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (1 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (2 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (3 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (4 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (5 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (6 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (7 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (8 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (9 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (10 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (11 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (12 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (13 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (14 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (15 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbooks: Scrapbook (16 of 16), 1935-1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)